# Rógvi Dávid Arge

### Data Science & Optimization Consultant

Phone: +45 5042 5002

E-mail: argeinnovations@gmail.com

LinkedIn: http://dk.linkedin.com/in/rogvidarge/en

GitHub: https://github.com/rogvid



### SUMMARY

Data Science Consultant with 3+ years experience in agile project development and a passion for machine learning and optimization. Vast experience in data wrangling, exploratory data analysis, machine learning and data visualization and applying these skills to generate corporate wide improvements. Expert at involving- and making the business take ownership of projects.

### **EXPERIENCE**

**Arge Innovations** | Owner & Data Science Consultant Dec. 2018 - Agile development and deployment of data science, and optimization products.

## Arge Innovations | Data Science Consultant - DFDS A/S Projects Dec. 2018 - May. 2019

- Helped migrate prediction algorithm to Python and guide the development and implementation of a scalable machine learning approach. New model decreased RMSE by 20%
- Scoped, developed, and deployed an optimization algorightm for transport operations
- Deployed dockerized Flask APIs and Frontends to DFDS Kubernetes cluster

#### **ATP=** | Data Scientist

Feb. 2017 - Dec. 2018

- Developed database monitoring system essential for our day to day work. We never missed
  a prediction because of database downtime since then
- Built machine learning model for finding citizens who reported false addresses. Allowed us to find people with complex fraud patterns
- Developed multiple expert systems designed to capture specific types of fraudulent behaviour

#### **ConWX** | Programmer & Data Analyst

Apr. 2015 - Feb. 2017

- Discovered and validated a way to improve forecasting for our clients by 10-25% vastly increasing client profit per month
- Designed and developed a monitoring system essential for forecast quality assurance and improvement

## Udacity Data Analyst Nanodegree Project Explore and Summarize Data

Feb. 2016

Scraped Boliga.dk and income statistics for people in Copenhagen. EDA showed an explosive increase in appartment prices around 500%, as well as the effects of the economic crisis on declining size of raises.

• Python • R • MongoDB • EDA • Data Wrangling

### **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATION**

Coursera Deep learning

2018

Deep Learning Specialization by Andrew Ng on the MOOC Coursera.

**Udacity** Data Analyst Nanodegree

2015 - 2017

Project based online education teaching essential knowledge and skills for data scientists.

Copenhagen University MSc in Physics

2012 - 2015

Focus on computational physics, machine learning and mathematical modeling.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Python Machine Learning Optimization Operations Research Data Visualization Data Analysis Modeling Statistics Git SOL D3 HTML **CSS** JavaScript C# Docker **AWS** Azure MongoDB

### **SOFT SKILLS**

Problem Solving
Critical Thinking
Communication
Adaptability
Project Planning
Decision Making
Scrum

### LANGUAGES

### **Native speaker**

Faroese Danish



### Professional proficiency

English

